HIGUERA HAROL

Aichi-ken Nagoya-shi Nakamura-ku 4-50 Taiko Dori, 504 Mansion Nakamura, 453-0811

Mobile: 070-1744-2311

Email: harolhiguera2005@gmail.com

http://harolhiguera.github.io/

CAREER OVERVIEW

Talented, honest and quick learner with solid theoretical and practical academic background in Electronics and Software Engineering, experienced in control design, analogue Electronic design, embedded systems, Android applications development and web programming languages, object oriented programming and good sense of design.

CORE STRENGTHS

- Electronic Engineering
- Fast Learner
- Programming and Design Skills
- Theoretical and practical engineering
- Creative
- General Math
- Open minded to multidisciplinary fields of engineering
- Good attention to detail and design
- · Deadline-oriented
- Committed
- Strong problem solving skills

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Electronic Circuit Design: Experience in embedded systems development, including control design, analogue circuit design, PCB development, UML, DRBFM, components selection and purchasing. Ability and experience in Kicad and Orcad Suite products for simulation and PCB design purposes.
- Android Application Development: Native development knowledge and experience on development of applications for Android Devices. Experience at working with IDEs such as Eclipse and Android Studio, able to work with GIT and delegate code responsibilities, able to make use of new support libraries and Android design patterns. Updated with the latest Android libraries and available open source tools.

Programming Languages: Java, php, SQL and XML.

- **Web Development:** Experience and knowledge in various programming languages for front and back end development as well as database implementation when is required: JavaScript, php, HTML, CSS, AJAX, MySQL, JQuery and JSON.
- Other software Skills: Illustrator, Photoshop, Matlab, Simulink, Labview, Ms Excel, Ms Word, Ms PowerPoint,

RELEVANT EXPERIENCE

10/2015 to Present Freelancer, Android Developer

Launchpad D Pty Ltd, Sidney, Australia

Android development of BLINK, and application to find and share venues around the user. Product based on concept and design. Development carried out in team. This job consisted on take full responsibility of the Android development component. Key

frameworks and libraries used: Retrofit, Glide, RXJava, Google API V2,

Facebook sdk.

Software tools: Android Studio, Illustrator, and Photoshop.

Currently working on IFISHCOMPS Android application, an app concept aimed to fishing lovers where catches and fishing events

can be shared.

04/2015 to 09/2015 Electronic Engineer, Control design

ASAHI VISION, Nagoya, Aichi, Japan

Product development engineer, In charge of control design for ophthalmic equipment, algorithms, and simulations. Software tools:

Matlab, Visual studio, UML.

10/2013 to 3/2015 Electronic Engineer, Android Developer

YOY – Bucaramanga, Colombia

Entrepreneur-Co founder. Electronic analogue design and control of a Robot for educational purposes. Programming of micro-controllers. PCB's circuit boards design. Development of an Android application to interact with the robot remotely. Software tools: Eclipse, Illustrator,

Kicad.

12/2012 to 04/2013 **Lecturer**

TEMPORARY UNION "CETICS", PROGRAM APPS.CO. MINISTRY OF

TELECOMMUNICATIONS - Bucaramanga, Colombia

Served as an Android lecturer and technical adviser at a program

for Entrepreneurs led by a government.

ADDITIONAL EXPERIENCE

07/2014 to 07/2014 Freelancer, Web developer

TSUNAGO – Tokyo, Japan

Responsive Front End development based on PSD design for Marketing Purposes. Technology used: HTML, CSS, CSS Media

Queries, JavaScript, and Photoshop.

02/2014 to 03/2014 Freelancer, Android Application developer

Uts.edu.co – Bucaramanga, Colombia

Development of an Android application that allows students to register subjects in an Educational Institution. Technologies used: Eclipse, NotePad++, SQL, Java, Php, PostgreSQL, XML and JSON.

EDUCATION

12/2013 **Bachelor of Science**: Electronic Engineering and

telecommunication systems.

INDUSTRIAL UNIVERSITY OF SANTANDER (UIS) – Bucaramanga,

Colombia.

2005-2008, 2011-2013

10/2012 **Seminar Course:** Android Systems and Geolocation Principles.

RADIOGIS, TELECOMMUNICATIONS RESEARCHING GROUP, UIS -

Bucaramanga, Colombia

10/2011 Language Studies: English and Business

PRINCES COLLEGE – London, United Kingdom.

Level: Fluent.

03/2014 to 03/2015 Language Studies: Japanese language

KYOTO INTERNATIONAL COMMUNITY HOUSE, Kyoto, Japan.Level: Basic Conversational, able to read and write in Hiragana

and Katakana.

ADDITIONAL TRAINING

11/2012 Training Course: Rotating Electric Machines (DC and AC

Motors)

NATIONAL LEARNING SERVICE, Medellin, Colombia.

Duration: 40 Hours.

10/2012 **Training Course**: Electronic product design with

microcontrollers.

NATIONAL LEARNING SERVICE, Cali, Colombia.

Duration: 40 Hours.